<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EcoComplex</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>EcoComplex</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu_4accc2c0008842f9.png</url>
      <title>EcoComplex</title>
      <link>https://example.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>XII Jornadas Nacionales de Ciencias del Mar.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/event/jornadasnacscimar2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/event/jornadasnacscimar2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including page elements such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesión temática &#34;Redes Tróficas&#34; en las XII Jornadas Nacionales de Ciencias del Mar</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/25-12-01-redes-jncm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/25-12-01-redes-jncm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nos encontramos ante la mayor crisis ecológica de la historia de la humanidad. La
acelerada pérdida de biodiversidad no solo afecta a las especies de manera individual,
sino que también tiene repercusiones a nivel ecosistémico. Las especies no existen en
aislamiento, sino que forman parte de complejas redes de interacciones que
estructuran los ecosistemas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para comprender los impactos del cambio global es
esencial entender el funcionamiento y la estabilidad de estas redes ecológicas. Las
interacciones entre especies en los ecosistemas pueden ser tróficas, mutualistas,
competitivas, amensalistas o comensalistas, y su estudio ha evolucionado desde las
primeras observaciones de naturalistas hasta la aplicación de herramientas analíticas
avanzadas. Las redes ecológicas proporcionan un marco conceptual y metodológico
para evaluar la estabilidad y resiliencia de los ecosistemas, permitiendo abordar el
impacto del cambio global y la pérdida de especies. En esta sesión temática, invitamos
a presentar trabajos que estudien redes ecológicas desde distintas perspectivas: desde
el análisis de interacciones hasta la modelización de redes complejas en ecosistemas
marinos y costeros; incluyendo contribuciones que exploren cómo las redes ecológicas
responden a perturbaciones ambientales y cómo su comprensión puede contribuir a la
conservación y manejo de los ecosistemas. A través de esta sesión, esperamos generar
un espacio de discusión sobre enfoques teóricos y aplicados que permitan avanzar en
la comprensión de las redes ecológicas y su papel en los ecosistemas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Amazon fire regimes under climate change scenarios</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-amazonas-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-amazonas-2025/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potter Cove&#39;s Heavyweights: Estimation of Species&#39; Interaction Strength of an Antarctic Food Web</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/rodriguez-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/rodriguez-2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why there are more species in several small patches versus few large patches: A multispecies modelling approach</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2024/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape composition and pollinator traits interact to influence pollination success in an individual-based model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/kortsch-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/kortsch-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The emergence of scale-free fires in Australia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/nicoletti-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/nicoletti-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Una revisión de los efectos de los cambios ambientales antropogénicos en las interacciones tróficas de 4 ecosistemas marinos entre los 45° y 62° S</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/marina-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/marina-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://example.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://example.com/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/tour/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PICT 2020 - Estudio de los bosques a nivel global: cambios de estado y alertas tempranas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/estudio-bosques-globales/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 17:01:41 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/estudio-bosques-globales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;resumen&#34;&gt;Resumen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uno de los cambios más importantes producidos por el hombre en el planeta es el reemplazo de las áreas de bosque con paisajes dominados por las actividades humanas. Este reemplazo produce la deforestación y constituye una de las principales causas de extinciones en el antropoceno. Una forma de entender los efectos de la deforestación es estudiar los fragmentos o parches de bosques, ya que la dinámica de estos parches es muy importante para el funcionamiento del bosque como un ecosistema.
La mayoría de las investigaciones sobre este tema estudian los parches a una escala local o regional, analizando la influencia de los tamaños, forma y cantidad de parches en la biodiversidad y en las funciones ecosistémicas. La disponibilidad de datos de cobertura de bosques a nivel global como también conjuntos de datos climáticos con la misma extensión ha permitido el estudio de la distribución de bosques a nivel planetario.
En estos casos se ha definido que existen estados alternativos a la cobertura de bosques como son la sabana y los pastizales. La posibilidad que una dada zona se encuentre bien en forma de bosque o bien remplazada por alguno de estos estados alternativos sugiere que esta problemática puede ser descrita en términos de una transición de fase entre esos estados observacionales. En este cambio de estado actúan como forzantes el clima, los cambios de régimen de fuegos y el disturbio antropogénico en forma de deforestación o reemplazo del bosque por plantaciones. Otro tema importante relacionado a los estados alternativos es la existencia de retroalimentación positiva en la dinámica del bosque, dado que la cobertura boscosa genera condiciones ambientales beneficiosas para su propio crecimiento, y ademas existe una retroalimentación con el clima, el bosque genera mayores precipitaciones y humedad ambiente. Los cambios de estado en forma general pueden ser descritos mediante dos tipos de comportamiento, en el caso de que el cambio de estado es discontinuo, es decir se produce un salto entre un estado y el otro se denomina transición de primer orden, cuando esto se produce de una manera continua (no hay salto) se llama transición de segundo orden. Se ha establecido la posibilidad de ambos tipos de transiciones principalmente en bosques tropicales.
Estos factores mencionados potenciados por la influencia humana a nivel global potencialmente pueden producir estos cambios de estado en grandes extensiones de bosques del planeta. Estas pueden constituir los llamados elementos de inflexión que podrían cambiar a un estado cualitativamente diferente mediante pequeñas perturbaciones y el punto de inflexión es el punto crítico correspondiente en el que el estado futuro del sistema se modifica cualitativamente.
Nuestro objetivo es estudiar las posible transiciones de los ecosistemas de bosques a nivel sub-continental, algunos de estos pueden considerarse elementos de inflexión del sistema terrestre, y determinar la cercanía a un punto crítico.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Determines Food Web Structure?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In nature species interact among each other in many ways. The most
common and studied interaction is that between a predator and its prey.
A food web can be defined as a network of interactions that describes
who eats whom in a certain ecosystem and at a certain time of the year.
In any ecosystem, in a terrestrial, freshwater or marine environment,
the so-called food web is comprised by lots of species (hundreds) and
interactions (thousands), showing a complex network of predator-prey
interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent paper in the Journal of Animal Ecology, we studied the
assembly process of food webs, that means how the complex network of
interactions is formed and which are the principal factors that drive
such processes. To put it in simple words, our research question was the
following: what determines the structure of a food web?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Florida Keys Mangrove Island. CC BY-SA 3.0,
https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?curid=11746362&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_da98d9a7e789d1b4.webp 400w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_ad4b6c5b8662215.webp 760w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_31a17bf82386ad8f.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_da98d9a7e789d1b4.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;571&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to previous investigations of colleagues we now know that the
structure of a food web is the result of community assembly, which is a
repeated process of species arrival, colonisation and local extinction.
This implies that there are two major components that determine the
structure of a food web: 1) the composition of species from where
individuals migrate to new habitats, referred to as the regional pool or
metaweb; and 2) a selective process that determines which species can
arrive and persist in the new habitat. We also know that the first to
colonise new habitats are species with a broad diet (i.e. great variety
of prey). Thus, predator-prey interactions are established during the
assembly process that begins the formation of a network of interactions:
the food web &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo;. Added to this, the characteristics of the
habitat (substrate, climatic conditions) and the dispersal capability of
the species are important factors that also control the assembly process
of the food web, determining which species might be able to persist in
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Long Pond Lake at Adirondacks Region. By Original uploader was Mwanner
at en.wikipediaLater version(s) were uploaded by XcepticZP at
en.wikipedia. - Transferred from en.wikipedia, CC BY-SA 3.0,
https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=4044745&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_c5c9e8b72aa2e7d3.webp 400w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_65ec33ce776dd55c.webp 760w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_87bc619efdc8dc38.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_c5c9e8b72aa2e7d3.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of a food web is ultimately constrained by the species and
potential interactions that exist in the regional pool, that is, the
metaweb. Such metaweb is shaped by evolutionary and biogeographical
processes that imply large spatial and temporal scales, containing many
habitats and communities. Each of the local communities can have
different food web structures, in terms of species and interactions
among them. Some theorists conceive of assembly as a non-Darwinian
selection process, whereby species and particular structures that
destabilise the food web will be lost and stabilising structures will
persist. Therefore, we should expect those stabilising structures to be
over-represented in local food webs compared to the metaweb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the hypothesis that the selective processes are responsible for
food web structure, we created an assembly model, where species migrate
from a regional pool and persist in a theoretical local food web given
at least one prey item available. The model considers
colonisation-extinction and secondary extinctions (i.e. if a species
arrives and none of its prey are present) events constrained by network
structure that is represented by predator-prey interactions. Thus, the
model does not include local selective processes and habitat constraints
that are thought to control the assembly process. Then we compared the
theoretical local food webs created from the assembly model with real
food webs. We hypothesised that, if local processes like stability
determine the food web structure, then we should observe a consistent
difference in the network structural characteristics between real food
webs and those assembled from the model. To test our hypothesis we
compiled 58 real food webs from a variety of regions and ecosystems: 2
marine food webs from Antarctica, 50 freshwater ones from the
Adirondacks region and 6 from an Arthropod community in six islands of
the Florida Keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Schematic diagram of the assembly model: species migrate from the
metaweb to a local food web carrying their potential interactions.
Predators become extinct if none of its prey are
present&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_7404c140bcd4c18f.webp 400w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_36e6b25c2e1e6c26.webp 760w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_59d1cd3763f5669.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_7404c140bcd4c18f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to our expectations, we found that most structural
characteristics didn&amp;rsquo;t differ between the real and modeled food webs. We
particularly compared properties related to stability, such as
modularity and the frequency of three-species motifs, and habitat
filtering and dispersal limitation, such as topological roles that
characterise how many interactions a species has within their module
and/or between modules (i.e. modules are formed by a group of species
that share more interactions compared to other species). This suggests
that evolutionary and biogeographical processes that are established in
the metaweb are more important and might drive the studied structural
characteristics in a food web than local processes such as habitat
filtering and dispersal limitations. In particular, our study forces us
to re-think the way we approach the study of food web structure. The
network properties that we as ecologists commonly use to shed light on
this aspect might be a by-product of the assembly process already driven
at the metaweb spatial and temporal scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.com/publication/saravia-2019/&#34;&gt;Check the complete publication here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Analysis Can Detect Changes In Food Web Stability Produced By Bottom Trawl Fishery In Patagonia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/funes-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/funes-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine food webs are more complex but less stable in sub-Antarctic (Beagle Channel, Argentina) than in Antarctic (Potter Cove, Antarctic Peninsula) regions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/rodriguez2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/rodriguez2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecological network assembly: how the regional metaweb influences local food webs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Network Interaction Model (SNIM) Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/snim-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 23:53:14 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/snim-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a beautifully simple ecological network model that can simulate predator-prey and competitive multispecies dynamics. This is the &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; model of the paper &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I read it long ago and for many years I wanted to make a version of it, finally, I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code here &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&lt;/a&gt;, to install it you need to clone it using &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; or download and compile it, following the instructions in the README will be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the description of the model from &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second model again involves a set of S (possible) species plus empty sites (pseudospecies
labelled 0). This set (the species pool) $\Omega(S)$ is then a discrete set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\Omega(S) = {0,1,2,&amp;hellip;,S}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where 0 indicates empty space, available to all species
from the pool. Three basic types of transition are allowed
to occur. Let us call $ A,B \in \Omega(S )$ two given spcies present at a given step. These possible transitions are summarized as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(i) Immigration: an empty site is occupied by a species randomly chosen from the set of (non-empty) species, i.e. $A \in \Omega(S )-{0}$:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$0 \xrightarrow{u_i} A$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This occurs with a probability of colonization (of empty sites) $\mu_i$ . Notice that this colonization depends on the particular species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ii) Death: All occupied sites can become empty with some fixed probability $e_i$ :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$A \xrightarrow{e_i} 0$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(iii) Interaction: the same rule as in model A is used, but here the probability of success $P_{ij}$ is weighted by the coefficients of the interaction matrix. Here we use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$P_{ij} = \pi[\Omega_{ij} - \Omega_{ji}]$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where $\pi[x]=x$ when $x &amp;gt; 0$ and zero otherwise. This probability of an interaction occurring in the system between species $i$ and $j$ is a measure of the interaction strength linking interacting species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to use it from &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the fun part is to make simulations, for that we need the parameters: there is an species parameter file and a simulation parameter file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the species parameter file is in the following example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Model parameters example 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;#
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;3 10000                  # 3 species, total habitat 10000
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;0.1 	0.1 	0.1      # Immigration vector
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;1 		1 		1        # Extinction vector
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Omega interaction matriz 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 0 is empty space
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 1 Predator eats 2 and 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 2 has higher growth rate 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 3 outcompete species 2 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;0.0 0.0 3.0 2.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;4.0 0.0 0.0 0.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;2.0 0.0 0.5 0.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lines that start with &amp;lsquo;#&amp;rsquo; are comments, then the first 3 lines define the general parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  first row define a total amount of habitat in our simulation, then the number of species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Species can migrate from the outside, this asumes that the habitat is sorrounded by a regional or bigger community that is the source of individuals. Then the 2nd. row is the immigration rate vector. Species can go locally extinct or death, we assume that they don&amp;rsquo;t live forever. And finally the &amp;lsquo;omega&amp;rsquo; or interaction matrix, the first column are the intrinsic growth rate of species, and the first row is a special species: the empty space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we need the simulation parameters, this is a simple example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Simulation parameters example 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;#
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;rndSeed = 0				# 0 means a random rndSeed
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;nEvals  = 500           # number of time steps
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;tau     = 0.01          # Integration step
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;iniCond = 1000          # Initial condition of abundance of species 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;                        # if only one number is specified all the species will have the same initial conditions
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So to run from &amp;lsquo;RStats&amp;rsquo; there is a set of functions included, and we need to set a global variable with the binary of the model. If we call &lt;code&gt;simul.cfg&lt;/code&gt; to the simulation file, and &lt;code&gt;model3.par&lt;/code&gt; to the parameters file the following code will run the model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Global path to the binary of SNIM model&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;snimBin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/Dropbox/cpp/CaNew/snim/dist/Release/GNU-Linux/snim&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;R/snim_functions.r&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;run_snim_plot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;simul.cfg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;model3.par&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;model.out&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_b32a73f3fea7cea1.webp 400w,
               /post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_c8340833e340e986.webp 760w,
               /post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_dc90963ab3f1fcb9.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_b32a73f3fea7cea1.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One nice addition to this plot is to add an annimation with the R package &lt;code&gt;gganimate&lt;/code&gt;, I only changed the &lt;code&gt;nEvals = 100&lt;/code&gt; in the simulation parameters file, and made another run of the model, then plot with the &lt;code&gt;out&lt;/code&gt; dataframe,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;gganimate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;ggplot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Species&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;aes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Density&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;colour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Species&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;            &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;geom_line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;theme_bw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;scale_y_log10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;xlab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Years&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;            &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;transition_reveal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34;
           src=&#34;https://example.com/post/snim-tutorial/SNIManimation3Species.gif&#34;
           loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sole, R. V, Alonso, D. &amp;amp; Mckane, A. (2002). Self-organized instability in complex ecosystems. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. B. Biol. Sci., 357, 667–681 &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production and Biomass of Seaweeds in Newly Ice-Free Areas: Implications for Coastal Processes in a Changing Antarctic Environment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/quartino-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/quartino-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Antarctic rocky coasts are mainly colonized by extensive macroalgal
communities, which play key roles as food resource, habitat and refuge for many benthic and
pelagic organisms. Due to climate warming, Antarctic marine ecosystems are being affected
by glacier retreat opening new habitats, e.g. newly ice-free areas that can be colonized by
macroalgae. As a consequence, primary production and fate of macroalgae are changing in
these new polar environments. In these ecosystems, the carbon production, especially from
large brown algae, is an important food source to the benthic invertebrate communities mainly
when other resources are scarce. Thus, in new areas colonized by macroalgae, the trophic
structure and biogeochemical fluxes can vary considerably. Moreover, when seaweeds die or are removed by water movement, ice scouring or storms, they are detached, fragmented and
degraded, incorporating and releasing particulate and dissolved organic matter to the coastal
food webs, i.e. they support a large fraction of the secondary production of the benthos. The
present chapter is a review of the knowledge of seaweed biomass and production in the
coastal Antarctic ecosystem opening a discussion on the role of these organisms as main
energy sources in e.g., small fjords and glacier influenced sites, impacted by recent climatic
change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productores primarios bentónicos en el ecosistema costero antártico - consecuencias del cambio climático (PICT)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/pict2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/pict2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Las algas bentónicas antárticas son importantes productores primarios, comprenden a los grupos de micro y
macroalgas que viven asociadas al fondo del mar y cumplen un papel esencial en los ecosistemas marinos. En la
Antártida, el microfitobentos se encuentra principalmente dominado por diatomeas (Zacher et al. 2007,
Campana et al. 2009, Wulff et al. 2011) y tiene un rol importante en el proceso sucesional ya que son las
primeras en colonizar el fondo rocoso (Zacher et al. 2007, Campana et al. 2017). Las macroalgas son fuente de
alimentación para organismos asociados al bentos (Amsler et al. 2005) y representan un aporte significativo de
materia orgánica particulada y disuelta a la trama trófica costera (Fischer y Wiencke, 1992). Además provén
hábitat y refugio para numerosos organismos bentónicos y bento-pelágicos (Wiencke y Amsler 2014).
En las últimas décadas se observó un marcado retroceso del glaciar que rodea caleta Potter, dejando al
descubierto áreas rocosas sin hielo, potencialmente aptas para ser colonizadas por macroalgas. A partir del
2008 se iniciaron una serie de estudios a fin de describir y cuantificar el efecto de las perturbaciones asociadas
al retroceso glaciario tales como el aumento en la carga de sedimento y la consiguiente disminución del grado
de penetración de la luz sobre la comunidad de algas bentónicas de la caleta. Las primeras observaciones
mostraron una notable presencia de algas en aquellos sitios donde antes no se encontraban presentes e
inclusive fueron registradas creciendo en sitios altamente disturbados próximos al glaciar (Quartino et al.
2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el ecosistema de caleta Potter las zonas costeras de fondos rocosos están mayormente colonizadas por
las grandes algas pardas endémicas Desmarestia menziesii J.Agardh, D. anceps Montagne e Himantothallus
grandifolius(A.Gepp &amp;amp; E.S.Gepp) Zinova. Estas macroalgas presentan los mayores valores de biomasa (Quartino
y Boraso de Zaixso 2008), son endémicas de la Antártida e islas adyacentes y están adaptadas a las
temperaturas frías extremas, por lo que podrían verse afectadas ante el inminente calentamiento global
(Wiencke y Amsler 2012). Un calentamiento creciente, junto con variaciones en la disponibilidad de luz en
zonas costeras, debido a la mayor carga de sedimento proveniente del agua de deshielo de los glaciares, podría
llevar a consecuencias imprevistas para los productores primarios bentónicos (macroalgas) y su fauna asociada.
Esto, a su vez, podría afectar el funcionamiento del ecosistema costero antártico, tal como ya lo han observado
en el Ártico (Bartsch et al. 2016), en donde se han registrado variaciones en la biomasa de las comunidades
1macroalgales, en la fauna asociada y en los invertebrados bentónicos (por ej., aumento de organismos
filtradores). De acuerdo a nuestros resultados iniciales se generan nuevos interrogantes acerca de la
adaptación de las macroalgas antárticas y su funcionamiento dentro del ecosistema marino, en este contexto
de cambio global.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redes de interacciones Ecologicas, la influencia del cambio global y la degradación del hábitat</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/ungs2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/ungs2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La explotación y la degradación de los hábitats naturales junto con el cambio climático producen la pérdida de especies y de servicios ecosistémicos. La manera en que las especies forman redes de interacciones determina su estabilidad y resistencia ante los disturbios. En este proyecto, proponemos estudiar las redes de interacción ecológicas incorporando los distintos tipos de interacción (tróficas, mutualistas y competitivas), los disturbios como el cambio de temperatura y la fragmentación del hábitat, que ensamblan las redes de interacción a diferentes escalas, desde la de comunidades locales a la biogeográfica. Acoplado a esto, investigaremos la fragmentación de uno de los ambientes terrestres más importantes, los bosques, a escala global, para producir señales de alerta temprana con respecto a la pérdida de biodiversidad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biodiversity Collapse and Early Warning Indicators in a Spatial Phase Transition between Neutral and Niche Communities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Food Web of Potter Cove (Antarctica): Complexity, Structure and Function</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/marina-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/marina-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture of Marine Food Webs: To Be or Not Be a ‘Small-World’</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/marina-2018-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/marina-2018-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Macroalgae Loss in an Antarctic Marine Food Web: Applying Extinction Thresholds to Food Web Studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/cordone-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/cordone-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Laws and Critical Fragmentation in Global Forests</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2018-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2018-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Network Interaction Model</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/stochastic-network-interaction-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/stochastic-network-interaction-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;snim&#34;&gt;SNIM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a C++11 implementation of a stochastic multispecies model. The model has multiple applications to investigate the relationship between ecological interactions (competition, predation) and diversity. It involves a discrete definition of individuals belonging to a given set of species. The dynamics are essentially probabilistic at the microscopic scale, but it leads to recognizable macroscopic patterns both in space and time. The model in is actual version is spatially implicit but a spatially explicit version is planned (never did it). You can find the source code at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more complete definition of the model can be found in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sole, R. V, Alonso, D. &amp;amp; Mckane, A. (2002). Self-organized instability in complex ecosystems. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. B. Biol. Sci., 357, 667–681 &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And check this presentation to see an application of the model &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17020.33929&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17020.33929&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life between Tides: Spatial and Temporal Variations of an Intertidal Macroalgal Community at Potter Peninsula, South Shetland Islands, Antarctica</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/marcias-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/marcias-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Method to Analyse Species Abundances in Space Using Generalized Dimensions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2015-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2015-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benthic Trophic Interactions in an Antarctic Shallow Water Ecosystem Affected by Recent Glacier Retreat</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/pasotti-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/pasotti-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earthworm Assemblages in Different Intensity of Agricultural Uses and Their Relation to Edaphic Variables</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/falco-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/falco-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mfSBA: Multifractal Analysis of Spatial Patterns in Ecological Communities [v2; Ref Status: Indexed, http://f1000r.es/347]</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Phytoplankton Bloom in Coastal Waters of Southern King George Island (Antarctica) in January 2010: An Exceptional Feature?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/schloss-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/schloss-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifractal Growth in Periphyton Communities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2012-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2012-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifractal Spatial Patterns and Diversity in an Ecological Succession</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2012/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algunas Cuestiones Sobre El Espacio En Ecología. Modelos, Datos y Aplicaciones</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Transients&#39; Dynamics in Spatially Extended Populations.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-2000/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Photographic Method for Estimating Chlorophyll in Periphyton on Artificial Substrata</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-1999/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Periphyton Dynamics in Running Water</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/saravia-1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/saravia-1998/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need for Biological Realism in the Updating of Cellular Automata Models</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/ruxton-1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/ruxton-1998/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
