<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | EcoComplex</title>
    <link>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lsaravia.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lsaravia.github.io/media/icon_hu_4accc2c0008842f9.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesión temática &#34;Redes Tróficas&#34; en las XII Jornadas Nacionales de Ciencias del Mar</title>
      <link>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/25-12-01-redes-jncm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/25-12-01-redes-jncm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nos encontramos ante la mayor crisis ecológica de la historia de la humanidad. La
acelerada pérdida de biodiversidad no solo afecta a las especies de manera individual,
sino que también tiene repercusiones a nivel ecosistémico. Las especies no existen en
aislamiento, sino que forman parte de complejas redes de interacciones que
estructuran los ecosistemas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para comprender los impactos del cambio global es
esencial entender el funcionamiento y la estabilidad de estas redes ecológicas. Las
interacciones entre especies en los ecosistemas pueden ser tróficas, mutualistas,
competitivas, amensalistas o comensalistas, y su estudio ha evolucionado desde las
primeras observaciones de naturalistas hasta la aplicación de herramientas analíticas
avanzadas. Las redes ecológicas proporcionan un marco conceptual y metodológico
para evaluar la estabilidad y resiliencia de los ecosistemas, permitiendo abordar el
impacto del cambio global y la pérdida de especies. En esta sesión temática, invitamos
a presentar trabajos que estudien redes ecológicas desde distintas perspectivas: desde
el análisis de interacciones hasta la modelización de redes complejas en ecosistemas
marinos y costeros; incluyendo contribuciones que exploren cómo las redes ecológicas
responden a perturbaciones ambientales y cómo su comprensión puede contribuir a la
conservación y manejo de los ecosistemas. A través de esta sesión, esperamos generar
un espacio de discusión sobre enfoques teóricos y aplicados que permitan avanzar en
la comprensión de las redes ecológicas y su papel en los ecosistemas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Determines Food Web Structure?</title>
      <link>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In nature species interact among each other in many ways. The most
common and studied interaction is that between a predator and its prey.
A food web can be defined as a network of interactions that describes
who eats whom in a certain ecosystem and at a certain time of the year.
In any ecosystem, in a terrestrial, freshwater or marine environment,
the so-called food web is comprised by lots of species (hundreds) and
interactions (thousands), showing a complex network of predator-prey
interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent paper in the Journal of Animal Ecology, we studied the
assembly process of food webs, that means how the complex network of
interactions is formed and which are the principal factors that drive
such processes. To put it in simple words, our research question was the
following: what determines the structure of a food web?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Florida Keys Mangrove Island. CC BY-SA 3.0,
https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?curid=11746362&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_da98d9a7e789d1b4.webp 400w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_ad4b6c5b8662215.webp 760w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_31a17bf82386ad8f.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://lsaravia.github.io/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Red_mangrove-everglades_natl_park_hu_da98d9a7e789d1b4.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;571&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to previous investigations of colleagues we now know that the
structure of a food web is the result of community assembly, which is a
repeated process of species arrival, colonisation and local extinction.
This implies that there are two major components that determine the
structure of a food web: 1) the composition of species from where
individuals migrate to new habitats, referred to as the regional pool or
metaweb; and 2) a selective process that determines which species can
arrive and persist in the new habitat. We also know that the first to
colonise new habitats are species with a broad diet (i.e. great variety
of prey). Thus, predator-prey interactions are established during the
assembly process that begins the formation of a network of interactions:
the food web &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo;. Added to this, the characteristics of the
habitat (substrate, climatic conditions) and the dispersal capability of
the species are important factors that also control the assembly process
of the food web, determining which species might be able to persist in
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Long Pond Lake at Adirondacks Region. By Original uploader was Mwanner
at en.wikipediaLater version(s) were uploaded by XcepticZP at
en.wikipedia. - Transferred from en.wikipedia, CC BY-SA 3.0,
https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=4044745&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_c5c9e8b72aa2e7d3.webp 400w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_65ec33ce776dd55c.webp 760w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_87bc619efdc8dc38.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://lsaravia.github.io/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/Long_Pond_lake_hu_c5c9e8b72aa2e7d3.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of a food web is ultimately constrained by the species and
potential interactions that exist in the regional pool, that is, the
metaweb. Such metaweb is shaped by evolutionary and biogeographical
processes that imply large spatial and temporal scales, containing many
habitats and communities. Each of the local communities can have
different food web structures, in terms of species and interactions
among them. Some theorists conceive of assembly as a non-Darwinian
selection process, whereby species and particular structures that
destabilise the food web will be lost and stabilising structures will
persist. Therefore, we should expect those stabilising structures to be
over-represented in local food webs compared to the metaweb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the hypothesis that the selective processes are responsible for
food web structure, we created an assembly model, where species migrate
from a regional pool and persist in a theoretical local food web given
at least one prey item available. The model considers
colonisation-extinction and secondary extinctions (i.e. if a species
arrives and none of its prey are present) events constrained by network
structure that is represented by predator-prey interactions. Thus, the
model does not include local selective processes and habitat constraints
that are thought to control the assembly process. Then we compared the
theoretical local food webs created from the assembly model with real
food webs. We hypothesised that, if local processes like stability
determine the food web structure, then we should observe a consistent
difference in the network structural characteristics between real food
webs and those assembled from the model. To test our hypothesis we
compiled 58 real food webs from a variety of regions and ecosystems: 2
marine food webs from Antarctica, 50 freshwater ones from the
Adirondacks region and 6 from an Arthropod community in six islands of
the Florida Keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Schematic diagram of the assembly model: species migrate from the
metaweb to a local food web carrying their potential interactions.
Predators become extinct if none of its prey are
present&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_7404c140bcd4c18f.webp 400w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_36e6b25c2e1e6c26.webp 760w,
               /post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_59d1cd3763f5669.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://lsaravia.github.io/post/what-determines-food-web-structure2022/MetaWebAssemblyModelFigure_hu_7404c140bcd4c18f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to our expectations, we found that most structural
characteristics didn&amp;rsquo;t differ between the real and modeled food webs. We
particularly compared properties related to stability, such as
modularity and the frequency of three-species motifs, and habitat
filtering and dispersal limitation, such as topological roles that
characterise how many interactions a species has within their module
and/or between modules (i.e. modules are formed by a group of species
that share more interactions compared to other species). This suggests
that evolutionary and biogeographical processes that are established in
the metaweb are more important and might drive the studied structural
characteristics in a food web than local processes such as habitat
filtering and dispersal limitations. In particular, our study forces us
to re-think the way we approach the study of food web structure. The
network properties that we as ecologists commonly use to shed light on
this aspect might be a by-product of the assembly process already driven
at the metaweb spatial and temporal scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lsaravia.github.io/publication/saravia-2019/&#34;&gt;Check the complete publication here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Network Interaction Model (SNIM) Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/snim-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 23:53:14 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/snim-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a beautifully simple ecological network model that can simulate predator-prey and competitive multispecies dynamics. This is the &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; model of the paper &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I read it long ago and for many years I wanted to make a version of it, finally, I did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code here &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&lt;/a&gt;, to install it you need to clone it using &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; or download and compile it, following the instructions in the README will be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the description of the model from &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second model again involves a set of S (possible) species plus empty sites (pseudospecies
labelled 0). This set (the species pool) $\Omega(S)$ is then a discrete set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$\Omega(S) = {0,1,2,&amp;hellip;,S}$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where 0 indicates empty space, available to all species
from the pool. Three basic types of transition are allowed
to occur. Let us call $ A,B \in \Omega(S )$ two given spcies present at a given step. These possible transitions are summarized as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(i) Immigration: an empty site is occupied by a species randomly chosen from the set of (non-empty) species, i.e. $A \in \Omega(S )-{0}$:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$0 \xrightarrow{u_i} A$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This occurs with a probability of colonization (of empty sites) $\mu_i$ . Notice that this colonization depends on the particular species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ii) Death: All occupied sites can become empty with some fixed probability $e_i$ :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$A \xrightarrow{e_i} 0$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(iii) Interaction: the same rule as in model A is used, but here the probability of success $P_{ij}$ is weighted by the coefficients of the interaction matrix. Here we use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$P_{ij} = \pi[\Omega_{ij} - \Omega_{ji}]$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where $\pi[x]=x$ when $x &amp;gt; 0$ and zero otherwise. This probability of an interaction occurring in the system between species $i$ and $j$ is a measure of the interaction strength linking interacting species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to use it from &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the fun part is to make simulations, for that we need the parameters: there is an species parameter file and a simulation parameter file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structure of the species parameter file is in the following example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Model parameters example 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;#
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;3 10000                  # 3 species, total habitat 10000
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;0.1 	0.1 	0.1      # Immigration vector
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;1 		1 		1        # Extinction vector
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Omega interaction matriz 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 0 is empty space
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 1 Predator eats 2 and 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 2 has higher growth rate 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Species 3 outcompete species 2 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;0.0 0.0 3.0 2.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;4.0 0.0 0.0 0.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;2.0 0.0 0.5 0.0
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lines that start with &amp;lsquo;#&amp;rsquo; are comments, then the first 3 lines define the general parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  first row define a total amount of habitat in our simulation, then the number of species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Species can migrate from the outside, this asumes that the habitat is sorrounded by a regional or bigger community that is the source of individuals. Then the 2nd. row is the immigration rate vector. Species can go locally extinct or death, we assume that they don&amp;rsquo;t live forever. And finally the &amp;lsquo;omega&amp;rsquo; or interaction matrix, the first column are the intrinsic growth rate of species, and the first row is a special species: the empty space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we need the simulation parameters, this is a simple example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;# Simulation parameters example 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;#
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;rndSeed = 0				# 0 means a random rndSeed
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;nEvals  = 500           # number of time steps
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;tau     = 0.01          # Integration step
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;iniCond = 1000          # Initial condition of abundance of species 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;                        # if only one number is specified all the species will have the same initial conditions
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So to run from &amp;lsquo;RStats&amp;rsquo; there is a set of functions included, and we need to set a global variable with the binary of the model. If we call &lt;code&gt;simul.cfg&lt;/code&gt; to the simulation file, and &lt;code&gt;model3.par&lt;/code&gt; to the parameters file the following code will run the model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# Global path to the binary of SNIM model&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;snimBin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/Dropbox/cpp/CaNew/snim/dist/Release/GNU-Linux/snim&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;R/snim_functions.r&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;run_snim_plot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;simul.cfg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;model3.par&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;model.out&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_b32a73f3fea7cea1.webp 400w,
               /post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_c8340833e340e986.webp 760w,
               /post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_dc90963ab3f1fcb9.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://lsaravia.github.io/post/snim-tutorial/model3_hu_b32a73f3fea7cea1.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One nice addition to this plot is to add an annimation with the R package &lt;code&gt;gganimate&lt;/code&gt;, I only changed the &lt;code&gt;nEvals = 100&lt;/code&gt; in the simulation parameters file, and made another run of the model, then plot with the &lt;code&gt;out&lt;/code&gt; dataframe,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34; data-lang=&#34;R&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;gganimate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;ggplot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Species&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;aes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Density&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;colour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Species&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;            &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;geom_line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;theme_bw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;scale_y_log10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;xlab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Years&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;            &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;transition_reveal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34;
           src=&#34;https://lsaravia.github.io/post/snim-tutorial/SNIManimation3Species.gif&#34;
           loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sole, R. V, Alonso, D. &amp;amp; Mckane, A. (2002). Self-organized instability in complex ecosystems. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. B. Biol. Sci., 357, 667–681 &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Network Interaction Model</title>
      <link>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/stochastic-network-interaction-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lsaravia.github.io/post/stochastic-network-interaction-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;snim&#34;&gt;SNIM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a C++11 implementation of a stochastic multispecies model. The model has multiple applications to investigate the relationship between ecological interactions (competition, predation) and diversity. It involves a discrete definition of individuals belonging to a given set of species. The dynamics are essentially probabilistic at the microscopic scale, but it leads to recognizable macroscopic patterns both in space and time. The model in is actual version is spatially implicit but a spatially explicit version is planned (never did it). You can find the source code at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lsaravia/snim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more complete definition of the model can be found in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sole, R. V, Alonso, D. &amp;amp; Mckane, A. (2002). Self-organized instability in complex ecosystems. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. B. Biol. Sci., 357, 667–681 &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rstb.2001.0992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And check this presentation to see an application of the model &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17020.33929&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.17020.33929&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
